<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on JNyman.com</title>
    <link>http://jnyman.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on JNyman.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jnyman.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert Code Camp 2017</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2017/10/15/desert_code_camp_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2017/10/15/desert_code_camp_2017/</guid>
      <description>Desert Code Camp 2017 was yesterday. I was slated to give four presentations yesterday. I ended up giving three.
Three of them were on F#. I did Introduction to F# in the morning and had two more ready to go in the evening. But by that time everyone in the morning had already gone home, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing, and so the evening attendees probably would have enjoyed hearing Introduction to F# again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Programming Yin Yang</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2017/07/23/database_programming_yin_yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2017/07/23/database_programming_yin_yang/</guid>
      <description>There are two different ways people like to write their SQL scripts when calling the database. One way is to write the SQL statements in their application code. Sometimes they will write an ORM to make this process similar to their language constructs. Sometimes they will write the SQL code directly in procedures.
Pros and Cons of Developing in the Application  Pros
 Low friction between application and database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Functional Programming in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2017/06/01/functional_js_talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2017/06/01/functional_js_talk/</guid>
      <description>This is the talk I gave at the JavaScript meetup in Phoenix. One the othe largest programming meetups in the valley.
Here are the slides to the talk.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s some books that can help you get ramped up into the functional programming paradigm Introducing functional programming with Underscore.js by Michael Fogus. And for a more in depth look into functional patterns Professor Frisby’s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Static Typing</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2017/02/12/the_power_of_static_typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2017/02/12/the_power_of_static_typing/</guid>
      <description>From what I understand static typing makes programmers more productive and gives implicit documentation to the code base - although explicit documentation is also very helpful. It also seems to make the tools we use much more powerful.
One of the problems of static typing is that your code becomes more verbose. With programming languages like F# the compiler will implicitly type as much of your program as possible. Where it fails, you need to type it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication and Authorization in ASP.NET Core</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2017/01/29/authentication_in_asp_net_core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2017/01/29/authentication_in_asp_net_core/</guid>
      <description>One thing that really got me frustrated in WebAPI 2.0 was creating custom authentication. Eventually I found a blog post by Rick Strahl that showed how to roll your own authentication/authorization. I wanted to implement a login (Basic Authentication) with username/password that would return a token for later (Bearer Authorization) use. It was quite simple but really frustrating because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of documentation on the subject.
Now I want to do something similar for ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# with Web API and Railway-Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/12/04/fsharp_with_webapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/12/04/fsharp_with_webapi/</guid>
      <description>I presented at the 2016 Desert Code Camp. The topic was WebAPI with F#. I also did a video series to go along with the talk. The talk and video series basically goes over how to use F# in a functional manner by building out all the pieces from scratch.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the series, hope you enjoy it!
F# WebAPI From Start to Finish.
Some set up steps and notes that are important to the success of the project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validation in F#</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/11/27/validation_in_fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/11/27/validation_in_fsharp/</guid>
      <description>The full code for this article is up on GitHub.
I like to the keep things as simple as possible and, ideally, reusable. At my previous employment I came up with a method of validation, but I was never entirely happy with the results. Some of the code repeated itself, and it was difficult to extend to arrays and array comparison. So, I went back to the drawing board building on top of the ideas that I created with the first validation library I created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swagger is too Restrictive</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/07/10/swagger_is_too_restrictive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/07/10/swagger_is_too_restrictive/</guid>
      <description>Swagger has a definite idea of what makes a good URL. But if you want to do anything outside of that good luck. I think, that even though it seems like a good idea to push people towards a standard it doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow the user to really create RESTful APIs which suit their own needs.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you have a reports resource. Sometimes you would like to get the JSON data of the report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript-Style Promises in F#</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/26/js_style_promises_in_fsharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/26/js_style_promises_in_fsharp/</guid>
      <description>Working in enterprise level back end software often times I need to get information from many different sources. When you have enough of these sources the time it takes to get all the information can really add up. That&amp;rsquo;s when F# async work flow really comes in handy. Except, there is a gotcha.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have two sources we need to fetch data from:
let myData () = async { let!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using NPM as a Build Tool</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/21/npm_as_build_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/21/npm_as_build_tool/</guid>
      <description>I really like simplicity. The tools I use, I like them to make my life easy, not hard. They need to work out of the box. No huge configuration settings, just make it easy so I can get to work.
Well, along come grunt, gulp, and now even more tools since I first started writing this that I won&amp;rsquo;t mention. Two build tools for JavaScript. Wonderful, we need tools to help us build our files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-the-Fly Lambda Expressions in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/13/lambda_expressions_in_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/13/lambda_expressions_in_javascript/</guid>
      <description>Before many of the JavaScript compilers became real popular and if you wanted to write in straight JavaScript you could create functions on the fly. This was really nice for doing lambda functions.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a couple libraries that did this.
https://github.com/fschaefer/Lambda.js https://github.com/dfellis/lambda-js
Here&amp;rsquo;s how it basically worked:
var f = function(func){ var funcArray = func.split(&#39;-&amp;gt;&#39;) return (funcArray.length === 1) ? new Function(&#39;x&#39;, &#39;return (&#39; + funcArray[0].trim() + &#39;)&#39;) : new Function(funcArray[0].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Convention Based Routes in Node.js</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/07/building_convention_based_routes_in_nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2016/06/07/building_convention_based_routes_in_nodejs/</guid>
      <description>Convention over configuration (also known as coding by convention) is a software design paradigm which seeks to decrease the number of decisions that developers need to make, gaining simplicity, and not necessarily losing flexibility.
 It seems in programming, if we haven&amp;rsquo;t learned the basic practices of others, we&amp;rsquo;ll end of repeating those practices; discovering them on our own. This isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a bad thing. It can be a good way to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Media Object</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/12/30/css_media_object/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/12/30/css_media_object/</guid>
      <description>I just finished attending the RockIt Bootcamp (12 week program). It&amp;rsquo;s a program that teaches the LAMP full stack development (Linux, Apache, mySQL, PHP). In the next little while I will be going over some of the things which I learned.
The css media object was first coined by Nicole Sullivan in 2010. It is still one of the most basic constructs to learn and understand in created good CSS content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular.js vs React.js vs Mithril.js</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/10/03/angular_vs_react_mithril/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/10/03/angular_vs_react_mithril/</guid>
      <description>Apparently Facebook has a bunch of functional-style programmers, not writing in ClosureScript though! https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IVvHPPcl2TM
http://youtu.be/nYkdrAPrdcw?t=40m30s &amp;gt; [Starts at 40 minute 30 seconds. Person asks question then Jing Chen &amp;gt; laughs at question, she must know how much Pete doesn&amp;rsquo;t like Angular.] &amp;gt; So, the question was comparing and contrasting&amp;hellip;React plus Flux and &amp;gt; Angular. &amp;hellip;[T]hey do solve some of the same &amp;gt; problems but they go at it in very different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bilby.js &amp; lenses</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/07/01/bilbyjs_lenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/07/01/bilbyjs_lenses/</guid>
      <description>In JavaScript nearly everything is mutable. This can cause problems in your code when you think you have a new object or variable but instead you are operating on the referenced object. So, we create patterns to alleviate this problem. Or we use libraries like underscore.js or lodash.js which incorporate the functional concepts. Unfortunately they don&amp;rsquo;t always use immutable objects either.
Bilby.js solves the mutability problem by using lenses. Using the lenses pattern one can access and change one&amp;rsquo;s objects in a safe and immutable manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match Expression for JavaScript?</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/20/match_expression_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/20/match_expression_javascript/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes (or rather most of the time) it would be nice to have more concise code in JavaScript. I was working with a function that needed quite a bit of if statements. if was awfully cluttered. I had looked at bilby.js examples and hadn&amp;rsquo;t realized that you can do multiple ternary expressions in a row.
So, instead of,
if (0){ return 0 } else if (1){ if (2) { return 1 } else if (3) { return 2 } else { return 3 } } else { return 4 }  You can do,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distributed &amp; Robust Feedly</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/12/distributed_robust_feedly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/12/distributed_robust_feedly/</guid>
      <description>In light of the recent attack on Feedly.com I thought it might be interesting to see other ways we could propogate data accross the Interent without being succeptible to attacks, or, at least less accessible.
With the approach outlined below we need to use an actual app instead of being able to use a browser (there might be a way to use a browser also, not sure how it would work though).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/07/javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/07/javascript/</guid>
      <description>I’ve jumped ship from Excel programming over to JavaScript (in a functional manner). I’ve also gone the way of Linux away from Windows. I love Excel and its power. But I see the writing on the wall and am moving to where I can hopefully get some work and starting making some moolah. You can follow my new blog over at http://thisisafiller.ghoster.io/.
If anyone is interested in the products I’ve made let me know how you like them and send me an e-mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototypes &amp; Compositions with Objects</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/04/prototypes_composition_with_objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/06/04/prototypes_composition_with_objects/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to figure out the best way to have functions be both compatible with an object oriented paradigm and a functional oriented paradigm when working on objects. My implementations are probably naive, but instructive nevertheless. It seems that lo-dash and other libraries have done a good job bridging those worlds.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have an object O such that
function O(a, b){ this.a = a this.b = b } var o = function(a, b){ return new O(a, b) }  Now, you want to extend the object but you also want the option to use the object in a more fuctional way with compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Immutability in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/29/functional_immutability_in_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/29/functional_immutability_in_javascript/</guid>
      <description>This is taken from Michael Fogus&amp;rsquo; book Functional JavaScript in the chapter Purity, Immutability, and Policies for Change.
Immutability is impossible to achieve in JavaScript without using Object.freeze but it only performs makes the object immutable shallowing, you have to roll your own deepFreeze if you would like to make the object truly immutable.
So there are some practices you can do to make your functions and variables perform in a more immutable manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional or Object Oriented JavaScript?</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/29/functional_or_oo_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/29/functional_or_oo_javascript/</guid>
      <description>When people are first exposed to JavaScript and its minimal set of tools (functions, objects, prototypes, and arrays), many are underwhelmed. Therefore, in order to “modify” JavaScript to conform to their idea of what it takes to model software solutions, they very often seek out or re-create class-based systems using the primordial ooze.
- Michael Fogus Functional Programming
 Of course, the next sentence he softens that quote, I just enjoyed the first part though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Monads, Monoids, and Make Believe</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/15/monads_monoids_and_make_believe_brian_lonsdorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/15/monads_monoids_and_make_believe_brian_lonsdorf/</guid>
      <description>with Brian Lonsdorf Working with Objects the better way var SSN = Constructor(function(number, current_user){ this.number = number this.user = current_user }) SSN.prototype = { fmap: function(f){ if(this.user.is_admin) return SSN(f(this.number), this.user) } } social.fmap(replace(&#39;-&#39;, &#39;&#39;)) //=&amp;gt; SSN(&#39;123456789&#39;, user) social.fmap(function(number){return number.reverse()}) //=&amp;gt; SSN(&#39;1234-56-789&#39;, user)  the functor way Note: Functor function defined.
var AdminAccess = Constructor(function(val, current_user){ this.val = val this.user = current_user }) Functor(AdminAccess, { fmap: function(f){ if(this.user.is_admin) return AdminAccess(f(this.val), this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes On Functional Programming</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/13/functional_programming_for_non_mathematicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/13/functional_programming_for_non_mathematicians/</guid>
      <description>Patterns for the Non-Mathematician with Brian Lonsdorf Lenses Using lenses for composable/polymorphic model manipulation.
E.g.,
var user = {id:1, name:{first:&#39;doris&#39;, last:&#39;day&#39;}} var L = makeLenses([&#39;name&#39;, &#39;first&#39;]) var firstNameChar = compose(L.name, L.first, _1) over(firstNameChar, toUpperCase, user) //=&amp;gt; {id:1, name:{first:&#39;Doris&#39;, last:&#39;day&#39;}}  Maybe Use Maybe (Haskell) types (Option types in bilby.js / Scala style) to make composition easier. This works with fmap (functor maps). Returns resultant option.
Error Handling (Either) Either(&#39;need an int&#39;, 3) //=&amp;gt; Right(3) Either(&#39;need an int&#39;, undefined) //=&amp;gt; Left(&#39;need an int&#39;) fmap(function(x){return x+1;}, Right(2)) //=&amp;gt; Right(3) fmap(function(x){return x+1;}, Left(&#39;need an int&#39;)) //=&amp;gt; Left(&#39;need an int&#39;) compose(fmap(f), Either(error))  Future Values I&amp;rsquo;ll have to come back to this one later when I use it more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bilby.js &amp; functional programming</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/13/bilby_functional_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2014/05/13/bilby_functional_programming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning functional programming for quite some time and like the programming paradigm. But, it can be difficult sometimes. Some libraries like lodash.js can be easy to start learning, but others like bilby.js require that you understand more of the functional approach. So, here are some videos that have helped me understand bilby.js better.
This one gives a quick overview. Note that Maybe (Haskell) is similar to Option (Scala)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet Budget Launched</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/10/28/spreadsheet_budget_launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/10/28/spreadsheet_budget_launched/</guid>
      <description>This first version is pretty basic - yet powerful. It will import your financial data from KMyMoney (I&amp;rsquo;ll add more financial programs later). Soon I will add report templates so you can easily view your finances - how you like it. It comes with an auto updater (wyUpdate) so you can stay up to date with the latest version with small packages.
Let me know what financial program you use so I can add it to the list for future compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bit Torrent Sync &amp; Updating/Installing Programs</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/09/30/bit_torrent_sync_updatinginsstalling_programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/09/30/bit_torrent_sync_updatinginsstalling_programs/</guid>
      <description>Bit Torrent Sync (BT Sync) is great software which can be used for syncing files. I use it for backing up all my pictures/videos/music/files/mobile computers. Well, I did some testing and it looks like it can be used for installing and updating software also.
I tested it with my Windows 8 computer over to my Windows XP computer. I created an Excel xla add-in file and I also created an executable file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zipping Files with VBA and USB Drives</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/08/19/zipping_files_with_vba_and_usb_drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/08/19/zipping_files_with_vba_and_usb_drives/</guid>
      <description>I used Ron de Bruin&amp;rsquo;s file zipping (and sending) code with Excel. It works great with a few tweaks. Unfortunately when someone is using a USB drive with their workbook on it it fails to work. So warning: Make sure the users are using it on the main computer when trouble shooting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUMIFS vs MATCH &amp; INDEX</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/03/14/sumifs_vs_match_index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/03/14/sumifs_vs_match_index/</guid>
      <description>I have one Time Card template setup with SUMIFS (used for Excel 2007 and above templates) and one set up with MATCH/INDEX (used for my 2003 and below templates). I tested the calculation speeds for each in Excel 2013 (preview) on Windows 8.
Here’s the VBA test code:
Sub test() Dim dTimer As Double Dim iLoops As Integer, iTotalIterations As Integer Dim wksStage As Worksheet Set wksStage = ThisWorkbook.Worksheets(&amp;quot;Staging Area&amp;quot;) iTotalIterations = 1 dTimer = Timer() For iLoops = 0 To iTotalIterations wksStage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming TimeCard Software Updates</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/03/13/coming_timecard_software_updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/03/13/coming_timecard_software_updates/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick update. I should be putting out the new Excel Time Card by the end of this week or early next week. This will be a big update. Including the following:
 Dashboard redesign (and Staging Area)  easily change jobs on chart easily change settings on dashboard filter jobs on chart, e.g., you have TimeCard and TimeCard:Marketing, you can just put TimeCard* to include both on the same screen  The template is now included in the program, so no need to download it  I&#39;m testing out a new updater so you can have secure and smaller packaged updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Extensions</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/25/excel_extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/25/excel_extensions/</guid>
      <description>Excel extensions extend the range object to use LinqTo2dArray (see also Codeplex). It also includes other extensions.
 RowsCount: Count total rows in all areas. Parse: Parse congruent range into an object by row-object arrays.  This doesn’t necessarily need to be congruent, in the future I may make it so it skips to different areas in the range.  ToArray: Copies the elements of the 2D object array row wise to a new array of the specified element type and length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinqTo2dArray</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/25/linqto2darray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/25/linqto2darray/</guid>
      <description>LinqTo2dArray written in C# (to allow iteration over the rows). Also found on CodePlex.
 Parse will take a 2D Array (not necessarily zero based) and load it into a class. Parse 2D object array into a class row wise. Compose will create 2D object array from enumerable type. Copies the elements of the 2D object array row wise to a new array of the specified element type and length.  using System; using System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attempted to Read or Write Protected Memory</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/12/attempted_to_read_or_write_protected_memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/02/12/attempted_to_read_or_write_protected_memory/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on switching over to a &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; machine (more on that in a new post). In the process my time card program stopped working with the following error:
System.AccessViolationException was unhandled Message: Attempted to read or write protected memory. This is often an indication that other memory is corrupt. Unfortunately this error doesn&amp;rsquo;t show up until well after it occurs. So you need to make some educated guesses as to where it is coming from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS for Old Blog Posts</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/01/16/rss_for_old_blog_posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/01/16/rss_for_old_blog_posts/</guid>
      <description>One of the nice to haves on my list is a way to read old blog posts via RSS. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that it is really easy to read someone&amp;rsquo;s old material on their blog if it is drip fed to me. Well, after a little searching on the internet I found Stream Spigot&amp;rsquo;s Feed Playback. Now I can enjoy someone&amp;rsquo;s old posts without having to remember to go back every other day or once every week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Write to Excel (2003) in Array</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2013/01/01/max_write_to_excel_2003_in_array/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2013/01/01/max_write_to_excel_2003_in_array/</guid>
      <description>I normally don’t deal with very long strings. But I’m working on a project that requires storing a text file in Excel that I can later access (it would be nice just to embed it but Excel doesn’t like viruses – which makes me have to just store it in a worksheet).
So what is the max string length in an array write to an Excel range?
911
Seems kind of random but that is the number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdvancedFilter Wrapper Engine</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/18/advancedfilter_wrapper_engine_for_vba_enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/18/advancedfilter_wrapper_engine_for_vba_enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>A while back ago I promised to produce my engine for the advancedfilter wrapper. Well, at the prodding of Hugo I finally put it together. I took the code from my VB.NET project and converted it to VBA. Man, that reminds of why I love .NET so much! If you ever get a chance to learn .NET of VBA definitely take the opportunity. At first it is difficult but then it gets to the point where you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Excel Functions - Code To Use List</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/05/list_of_excel_functions_code_to_use_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/05/list_of_excel_functions_code_to_use_list/</guid>
      <description>I saw a few people were downloading my list of Excel functions that I created. I thought it might be useful show the code that I use to get that data to a manageable format. Although the code is written in VB.NET it should be easily converted to VBA.
[wpdm_file id=3]
I use a simple structure (type in VBA) for the data.
Private Structure ExcelFunctionInfo Dim Name As String Dim Category As String Dim ExcelVersion As Integer Dim Description As String Dim Syntax As String Dim URL As String End Structure  I then just loop through the data in the string that was gotten from the text file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Queries</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/03/excel_queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/12/03/excel_queries/</guid>
      <description>I came across some nice libraries to use while programming to query Excel. Right now I’m am using the standard COM interface for my projects, which is fine for small ranges (which is true for most users – I would assume). But for large ranges I would need something more powerful.
LinqToExcel
LinqToExcel appears to be a great project for using a Linq interface to query Excel (but not write to Excel).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter Now Available and Other Muses</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/11/08/scribble_filter_now_available_and_other_muses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/11/08/scribble_filter_now_available_and_other_muses/</guid>
      <description>I got the sale software all installed so I can sell the Scribble Filter. There’s still a few changes I wanted to make with it. I wasn’t entirely thinking when I added the ability to filter ranges directly when I add (among others). I should have made it more compliant to what Microsoft does. I’ll be working on changing that around now. It will probably be a little while before I incorporate all of that into the filter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter (For Excel)</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/11/01/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/11/01/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_4/</guid>
      <description>Points discussed in video:
The scribble filter is a text wrapper for the Advanced Filter in Excel, making it easy to work with and adding new capabilities.  Use both {AVERAGE} function and Excel AVERAGE function @00:04 Click on Excel function with cursor to goto Excel&amp;rsquo;s function web page @01:18 Using ranges as a formula. @01:33 
 Scribble Filter Home Scribble Filter Help
Overview Part 1 Overview Part 2 Overview Part 3 Overview Part 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter: Installation &amp; Opening</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/31/scribble_filter_installation_opening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/31/scribble_filter_installation_opening/</guid>
      <description>The scribble filter is a text wrapper for the Advanced Filter in Excel, making it easy to work with and adding new capabilities.
Points discussed in video:
 Installing @00:06 Open Scribble Filter Dialog @00:30   Scribble Filter Home Scribble Filter Help</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter (For Excel)</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/22/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/22/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_2/</guid>
      <description>Points discussed in video:
The scribble filter is a text wrapper for the Advanced Filter in Excel, making it easy to work with and adding new capabilities.
 Filter in place @00:08 Copy filtered data to different worksheet @00:32 Chaining filters @00:57 Special Report (Sum column by unique values in different column) @1:11 Overwriting previous reports @01:37   Scribble Filter Home Scribble Filter Help
Overview Part 1 Overview Part 2 Overview Part 3 Overview Part 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter (For Excel) Overview Part 3</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/22/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/22/scribble_filter_for_excel_overview_part_3/</guid>
      <description>Points discussed in video:
The scribble filter is a text wrapper for the Advanced Filter in Excel, making it easy to work with and adding new capabilities.
 Special Functions Defined @00:04 Top or bottom (also purpose for chaining) @00:30 Top or bottom by percent @02:10 Above or below average @02:52  Scribble Filter Home
Scribble Filter Help
Overview Part 1
Overview Part 2
Overview Part 3
Overview Part 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribble Filter Overview Part 1</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/15/scribble_filter_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/10/15/scribble_filter_overview/</guid>
      <description>Points discussed in video:
The scribble filter is a wrapper for the Advanced Filter in Excel, making it easy to work with and adding new capabilities.
 To get the date spans right click on the left calendar button. Use tab or enter to get the first line from the drop down menu. Right click on buttons to get more options (e.g., right click on report button to set type of report to create: On separate sheet, preview, in place, chain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheet Exists</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/09/13/sheet_exists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/09/13/sheet_exists/</guid>
      <description>I was looking at Siddharth Rout&amp;rsquo;s new blog (Adding/Deleting Sheets to the Excel File) and realized that I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted my version of sheet exists. Mine probably does too much per Code Complete standards, but it is nice not to have to think of multiple.
If I were to refactor this code I would take out the code for the charts and probably just make it work only for checking if the sheet exists and adding a new sheet if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Excel Functions</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/27/list_of_excel_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/27/list_of_excel_functions/</guid>
      <description>For the advanced filter I need a list of Excel functions. There are lists, unfortunately I needed the list with the function parameters (syntax). I also wanted it by date. I have lists of just the functions for Excel 2003, 2007, and 2010 without the syntax. So I did some screen scraping of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s list of Excel functions where I was able to get the function name, category, description, syntax, and website URL for that function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML Comments</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/27/xml_comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/27/xml_comments/</guid>
      <description>Comment headers above procedures can be convenient when you want to know what a function does and what the parameters are for – especially if they weren’t named with enough description. Luckily Visual Studio provides a way to do these comments easily and it gives you intellisense for your own functions! They are called XML comments. All you need to do is put in three comment markers (‘) and then it will fill in everything for you (if you already have the procedure/parameters filled in).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdvancedFilter: Parsing the Search String</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/06/advancedfilter_parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/08/06/advancedfilter_parsing/</guid>
      <description>One of the most difficult parts of creating an advanced filter class is figuring out how to parse the search data and turn it into a 2D array, which Excel can understand. I figured my user interface will be a string. So I started there. In my original implementation of the search algorithm it wasn’t very robust, so this time around I figured I would do it “right.”
Well, right is a relative term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm Resources</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/07/16/algorithm_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/07/16/algorithm_resources/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was reading through Code Complete a classic coding book that is widely considered one of the best practical guides to programming, Steve McConnell’s original CODE COMPLETE has been helping developers write better software for more than a decade. And he mentioned algorithm books. What, there exists algorithm books? You mean I don&amp;rsquo;t need to come up with this code all by myself? Combined with the internet to figure out what exactly these algorithms are called, they could be a huge help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Card Alternatives</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/19/time_card_alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/19/time_card_alternatives/</guid>
      <description>In addiction to the Excel Time Card you can use these:
The time card is my pilot program to learn how to do the personal finance add-in better. I chose not to charge for the time card simply because there are already many time tracking things out there, like SlimTimer (if I needed one for on the go I would probably use this one, nice and clean and easy to use), ClickTime, RescueTime (this one is an interesting concept where it tracts your time for you), and TimeCard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pivot Tables as a Staging Resource</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/19/using_pivot_tables_as_a_staging_resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/19/using_pivot_tables_as_a_staging_resource/</guid>
      <description>When I originally created the Excel time card dashboard I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to back my data with any pivot tables. I soon found though that it slowed the calculations so much that I needed to use pivot tables just to make it bearable to work with the dashboard. The reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use pivot tables was because they are prone to do wacky and unexpected things.
So, what I have done is I automated some of the code to fix errors (like make sure that the &amp;ldquo;wksPivotTable&amp;rdquo; has a column for months and years and that it is in order).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Types</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/18/generic_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/18/generic_types/</guid>
      <description>Last time we went over Overloading function in .NET. Today we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at generics. I had been wondering how to do this for some time, seeing that I could do it with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s built in code. I have to say, it is pretty nice and really makes coding much easier and cleaner.
A generic type is a single programming element that adapts to perform the same functionality for a variety of data types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overloading in VB.NET</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/07/overloading_in_vb_net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/06/07/overloading_in_vb_net/</guid>
      <description>In previous posts I showed how you can use Extensions and Lambda Expressions to make some pretty versatile functions in .NET. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll show a method that really helps for the readability and organization of your code.
In the past we used optional parameters to make a function do multiple things. We even needed to make new functions that did pretty much the same thing in order to make it better organized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Time Card Completed</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/05/16/excel_time_card_completed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/05/16/excel_time_card_completed/</guid>
      <description>The Excel time card I have been working on is completed. Feel free to have a look and tell me what you think! I still need to add more documentation, which I will role out in the future let me know if you have any questions or found any bugs!
Got to the download page to get it!
A screen cast that shows some features of the time card stamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Class Made from a Shaped Recordset</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/05/11/a_class_made_from_a_shaped_recordset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/05/11/a_class_made_from_a_shaped_recordset/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some fun code that I worked on a while back. This disconnected record set is what you call a shaped record set, created on the fly. It is a pretty complex class all wrapped in one nice little bundle. Unfortunately it goes terribly slow. Creating a class with the dictionary object in the Scripting Runtime Object Library should be the fastest, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for speed.
Pretty crazy looking code, but pretty elegant once you get used to looking at code like that, unfortunately it&amp;rsquo;s not very using for creating classes on the fly, or even instead of regular classes (It would make making classes a synch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugelkultur Beds</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/16/sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/16/sc/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to gardening, I have a black thumb. But every year I try as I might to garden again. Last year I tried mixing some wood and branches into my square boxes inspired from the hugelkultur bed design. This seemed to have a positive effect on my garden and helped it retain water better.
So this year, I&amp;rsquo;m at it again, but on a bigger scale.
&amp;nbsp;
8 feet by 4 feet wide by 3 feet deep pit for wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambda Expressions</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/14/lambda_expressions_an_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/14/lambda_expressions_an_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Another thing that I like about programming in .NET beyond LINQ and Extensions is lambda expressions. (It should be noted that LINQ, Extensions, and lambda expressions are all related). Lambda expressions are &amp;ldquo;are callable entities that are defined within a function, you can return a lambda expression from a function and you can pass lambda expressions to other functions.&amp;rdquo; Lambda expressions come with the System.Core library, so no need to add a reference nor Imports at the top of your class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linq: An Introduction</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/11/linq_an_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/11/linq_an_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Another thing that I like about programming in VB.NET beyond Extensions is LINQ. LINQ is similar to SQL in structure - which is &amp;ldquo;a declarative programming paradigm that expresses the logic of a computation without describing its control flow.&amp;rdquo; So LINQ takes declarative paradigm and applies it to object oriented programming.
What&amp;rsquo;s so great about this? Well, it does slow the program down, but it speeds up the the programming process, puts the information in a form that is more descriptive (although that is no excuse not to thoroughly comment your code), and makes programming easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions in VB.NET</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/05/extensions_in_vb_net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/04/05/extensions_in_vb_net/</guid>
      <description>Learning how to use VB.NET can be quite the leap from VBA, but once you start learning VB.NET and have much more control it’s difficult to want to go back to VBA.
One of the things that I like about VB.NET is methods. Extensions allow you to extend data type methods. So, let’s say you have a String data type (Strings in VB.NET are like a class in and of themselves) and you want it to have the method of appending “]” at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why UDF Array Functions are Faster</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/29/why_udf_array_functions_are_faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/29/why_udf_array_functions_are_faster/</guid>
      <description>Over at FastExcel the answer was given why UDF arrays go faster to the question I had on why UDF array formulas are faster than regular formulas. I had forgotten about this post that he had written.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the answer that he gives. Check out his blog post to see more of the details of why this is. You can break down the time taken by a VBA UDF into these components:  Overhead time to call the UDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculation Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/28/calculation_effeciency_array_formulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/28/calculation_effeciency_array_formulas/</guid>
      <description>Chandoo had some posts on speeding up Excel worksheets, one of the posts focuses on formulas and another he let the general readers make their suggestions. I made the suggestion that people use array formulas. But most of the other suggestions said not to use array formulas since they slow down your spreadsheet. Needless to say, I was a bit confused, I have seen quite the performance boost from using array formulas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/23/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/23/updates/</guid>
      <description>AdvancedFilter Class
Just so everyone knows. I&amp;rsquo;m going to postpone the AdvancedFilter series until I start working on it in .NET, that way I&amp;rsquo;ll remember more about what I was doing before. I&amp;rsquo;ll start working on that when I finish up the Time Card application and the Chart Manipulator.
Time Card
I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be finishing up the beta version of the time card until early April. I&amp;rsquo;m currently debugging the UDF function &amp;ldquo;SumDate&amp;rdquo; which is pretty central to the time card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problems Of Copy/Pasting Code</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/14/the_problems_of_copy_pasting_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/14/the_problems_of_copy_pasting_code/</guid>
      <description>Copying and pasting is great for coding, but sometimes it can be pretty silly if you make a mistake in the code. Here’s a triple copy/paste fail (the values should be set to true):
Public Sub SheetActivate_Dashboard(ByVal sh As Object) Try gXLApp.EnableEvents = False OpenTimeStamp() Finally gXLApp.EnableEvents = False End Try End Sub Public Sub SheetDeActivate_Dashboard(ByVal sh As Object) Try gXLApp.EnableEvents = False If Not gfTimeStamp Is Nothing Then gfTimeStamp.Visible = False gfTimeStamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdvancedFilter Class Part 3</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/02/advancedfilter_class_part_3_creating_the_sub_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/03/02/advancedfilter_class_part_3_creating_the_sub_class/</guid>
      <description>In order to get the nice drop down menu we&amp;rsquo;ll need a second class I&amp;rsquo;ll call &amp;ldquo;SearchTerms.&amp;rdquo; This class is also necessary to store each individual search term entered into the class. Included in this class will be:  Search Term Header Header Operator Match Type 
&#39; SearchTerms &#39; Description: This class contains the search information. &#39; &#39; Authors: Jon Nyman, www.spreadsheetbudget.com &#39; &#39; Change Overview &#39; Date Comment &#39; -------------------------------------------------------------- &#39; 03/02/2012 Initial version &#39; Option Explicit &#39;--------------------------------------------------------------- &#39;Class Variable Declarations &#39;--------------------------------------------------------------- Private msSearchTerm As String Private msHeader As String Private meHeaderOperator As HeaderOperator Private meMatchType As MatchType &#39;--------------------------------------------------------------- &#39;Class Property Procedures &#39;--------------------------------------------------------------- Property Get SearchTerm() As String SearchTerm = msSearchTerm End Property Property Let SearchTerm(ByVal sItem As String) msSearchTerm = sItem End Property Property Get Header() As String Header = msHeader End Property Property Let Header(ByVal sHeader As String) msHeader = sHeader End Property Property Get Header_Operator() As HeaderOperator Header_Operator = meHeaderOperator End Property Property Let Header_Operator(ByVal eHeaderOperator As HeaderOperator) meHeaderOperator = eHeaderOperator End Property Property Get Match_Type() As MatchType Match_Type = meMatchType End Property Property Let Match_Type(ByVal eMatchType As MatchType) meMatchType = eMatchType End Property  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Settings Class in VBA</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/29/creating_a_settings_class_in_vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/29/creating_a_settings_class_in_vba/</guid>
      <description>In .NET they have a nice settings class you can create using ApplicationSettingsBase base class. In VBA it takes a bit more work to get it working, but can be fairly elegant if done correctly.
Some criteria that is needed for a settings class in vba are:  Well formed Fast lookup Default setting Single input/output procedures.  To make it well formed I used an enumeration variable type to create each setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdvancedFilter Class Part 2</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/15/advancedfilter_class_part_2_determining_what_options_we_want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/15/advancedfilter_class_part_2_determining_what_options_we_want/</guid>
      <description>The first thing we’ll want to do is determine what macro options we would like in the class.
The options I currently have are:
 Range to filter (optional – can use current range instead). Filter location (optional – if you are using an add-in then you can place in there, otherwise can put in temporary sheet). Filter action (copy to new range or filter in place (default)). Get unique items from a column (will need to use different method than AdvancedFilter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapping a Class Around the AdvancedFilter Method</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/10/wrapping_a_class_around_the_advancedfilter_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/02/10/wrapping_a_class_around_the_advancedfilter_method/</guid>
      <description>Classes are a tool in object-oriented programming that make programming much simpler. One class that I have developed in VBA is a class that makes using the AdvancedFilter method extremely easy and useful. In fact, I like it so much that I stopped using the regular find method. In the coming weeks I will demonstrate how this was done.
 This is how the AdvancedFilter method works:   Use a predefined range to filter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributing Add-ins via Installer</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/27/distributing_add_ins_via_installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/27/distributing_add_ins_via_installer/</guid>
      <description>Recently I needed to create an installer for my add-ins using Inno Setup installer. Inno Setup is a free ware professional installer. It lets you use Pascal to create special code to help you install the add ins.
Luckily, over at Dutch Gemini’s website he has helped with plenty of the code to get there. Very well done, I might add.
It looks like he uses a single add-in file for Excel 2003 and below and Excel 2007 and above (for ribbon purposes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and Modeless Forms</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/23/dot_net_and_modeless_forms_in_excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/23/dot_net_and_modeless_forms_in_excel/</guid>
      <description>When I was doing some programming in VB.NET (for the Time Stamp program), I tried putting a modeless form in Excel. It came up as a new window in the task bar but then wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually show on the screen. When I did a modal form it would show on the screen but also in the task bar.
.NET let&amp;rsquo;s you choose the parent window of your form. I found some code on StackOverflow in C# that gives you the proper owner window in IWin32Window form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Range Address from Number to Letter</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/20/range_address_from_number_to_letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/20/range_address_from_number_to_letter/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, before I realize it (and, I’m sure, others too) I do a bunch of work, that turns out that I didn’t need to do before. The RangeAddress function that I created is a perfect example of this. This function goes from a column number to a letter and returns the whole string range address. I started off with someones else’s code. I then made it work for me. Their code only worked for Excel 2003 and below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Last Cell</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/13/find_last_cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/13/find_last_cell/</guid>
      <description>Finding the last cell is a common thing people look for when they are coding in VBA. I made a function that does this automatically for me when I am looking for the last cell. In conjunction with the RRange function this simplifies the programming life for VBA significantly.
Heres some example code on how to use the function FindEnd.
Sub FindEndExamples() Dim l As Long &#39;Find last row in column 2 on current worksheet l = FindEnd(2) Debug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Range from Row &amp; Column Numbers</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/12/get_range_from_row_and_column_numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/12/get_range_from_row_and_column_numbers/</guid>
      <description>Before I created a quite elaborate code to get the column letter from the column numbers. It turns out that it was much easier than I had thought before. So in the code below I’ve simplified it considerably by using the Cells method.
In the function below I use a function called FindEnd.
&#39;RRAnge &#39; -------------------------------------------------------------- &#39;Comments: This Function returns the desired range. &#39; &#39;Arguments: lRow First cell row number. &#39; lCol First cell column number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon...</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/coming_soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/coming_soon/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on a time card that will allow the user to track their time in Excel. This will allow the user to choose multiple projects at once and produce charts as a great visual to see how you are working.
After that I will work on my advanced find in VB.NET.
The long term project is the spreadsheet budget in Excel. This project is expected for first release in mid 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Data from Excel to VBA</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/import_data_from_excel_to_vba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/import_data_from_excel_to_vba/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted a function that can get me data from excel in a format that will always be the same. Sometimes I get the data and I expect a 2D variant array but instead get a string or double value. So I created a function to make it easy for myself, getting the same format that I expect.
&#39;ImportExcelData &#39; -------------------------------------------------------------- &#39;Comments: This Function imports excel data in different formats (1D, 2D, or String).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/0welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jnyman.com/2012/01/04/0welcome/</guid>
      <description>I decided that using Drupal was more work than I wanted to put into my website, so here&amp;rsquo;s to WordPress! Hopefully I won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my previous entry for this post:
Welcome to SpreadsheetBudget.com. This is my blog that will demonstrate ideas and learning material as I create a budget spreadsheet using Excel. Once I finish creating the software, or at least get closer, I will begin to publish how to articles on how to use the software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>